# Fei Tian

Email: ftian@mum.ca

Tel: 709-986-6307

Address: 7 Calvin Ave

Software Developer Android Developer

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly resourceful technology savvy. Software developing and testing with experience in Java and Android SDK.

Web developing in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP. Committed to technological advancement and Developer role.

Proven experience and success working within application development environments, individually and as a team member.

Comprehensive understanding on development, design, testing, debugging and documentation of applications.

#### **KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Java (3 years)

Android SDK (2 years)

HTML (1 year)

Java Script (1 year)

CSS (1 year)

MySQL (1 year)

C++, PHP, RESTful, third-party API(1 year) Eclipse, Android Studio, Dreamweaver, XAMPP, Github

#### **PROFILES**

https://franktian0906.github.io

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

#### Take Home App (Android OS, MySQL)

Sept 2018

- Developed airline routes searching system by using the IATA city codes to create route suggestion page for users' review
- Utilized Local SQLite with 10000+ data sources, and created animation
- Embedded the third-party API on Google Map of Android API
- CODE: https://github.com/FrankTian0906/TakeHome

#### Tian Fei's Website (JavaScript HTML CSS)

Aug 2018

- Showed Personal information and summary for personal projects and work experience
- Utilized video demo, shutters effect to pop content automatically by mouse hover
- Embedded the internal web page positioning
- CODE: http:// franktian0906.github.io

## Sport Partner App (Android OS, PHP, MySQL)

June 2017- Dec 2017

- Developed the application 'Go Up', collected and recorded sport data of stairs climbing, and reflected the pattern of data on the visible line charts for the user
- Created client and server communication form on RESTful/ JSON
- Utilized the pressure sensor detector on mobile to periodically collect data statistics from users
- Embedded the third-party API which indicated data usage with MPAndroidChart library to perform the data pattern.
- Built the database by using the PHP to connect user data and commend on MySQL database.
- CLIENT CODE: https://github.com/FrankTian0906/ClimbingStairs
- SERVER CODE: https://github.com/FrankTian0906/ClimbStairs\_Server

#### The Circuit Simulation System (Java)

Jan 2017- Apr 2017

- Simulated circuit function for users to draw a circuit diagram by building gates and links; set input value for users to generate result;
- Used MVC design mode to construct the frame work
- Drew the variant circuit gates with JFrame library
- Created the automatic spot detection; drew the gates and links between each terminal
- Set signals to transport the command the output result
- CODE: https://github.com/FrankTian0906/CircuitSimulator

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Teaching Assistant in Memorial university

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

- City of St. John's, NL
- Supervised students during lab class time and organized activities
  Worked closely with the lead TA to identify issues that students encountered and developed appropriate solutions
- Assisted with classroom instruction in Java Class; provided support and guidance to students

#### Technology Supporter in Inspur Inc.

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

City of Taiyuan, China

- Installed and maintained the logistics system for clients
- Reported user's data to create the backed-up data
- Guided customers to operate the system and answered general inquires

**EDUCATION** 

Master of Applied Science (Computer Engineering)

Jan 2016 - Jan 2018

GPA 3.7/4.0

Memorial University, St. John's, NL

Bachelor of Computer Science (Network Engineering) GPA 8.1/10

Sept 2009 - Jul 2013

North University of China, Taiyuan City, China